

For the past year, I've been on a career break, focusing on my very young kids (three, three years and under, baby!). Before that, I was a Principal Software Engineer for Microsoft, working on storage performance for the Azure cloud. I graduated from Brown University with a B.S. in Computer Science in 2013.

I love computer systems! I have experience working on distributed data systems, multithreaded native code optimization, storage drivers, RDMA networking, and kernel programming. I also have interests in computer graphics, cryptography and operating systems.

I love to learn and teach! I used to do a well-loved 1½ hour "boot camp" technical presentation on Azure Storage a few times a year, and I was a teaching assistant for 6 classes over 5 semesters during my undergrad.

### Work Experience

## Principal Software Engineer, Azure Storage, Microsoft, 2017-2021

- Next-gen proof of concept for high performance Azure virtual machine disks
  - Spearheaded project based on own performance analysis, and obtained buyoff for project
  - Co-designed and developed optimized, wire-compatible implementation of Azure disk engine
  - Achieved >1 million IOPS per node with sub-millisecond latency, an orders-of-magnitude improvement
- Contributed to a project optimizing internal network data flow using InfiniBand RDMA
- Designed and gave in-depth tech talk for onboarding new hires ("Azure Storage Boot Camp")
  - Organically grew from notes to a talk to headliner of new all-day "boot camp" event
  - I was flown out to give my talk at our Shanghai, Hyderabad and Bengaluru offices

# Software Engineer II, Windows Deployment, Microsoft, 2013-2017

- Lead a ground-up rebuild of key components for Window's 'Reset this PC' recovery feature, which dramatically reduced failure rate
- Traveled overseas to work with PC manufactuers on customizing recovery for their devices

### Teaching Assistant for Brown University Computer Science, 2010-2013

- For graduate- and undergraduate-level courses in graphics, operating systems, and cybersecurity
- As regular TA, developed course materials, graded assignments, ran coding labs and held office hours
- As head TA, hired and managed teams of undergrad TAs, organized courses, developed course content

#### **Patents**

• <u>US 9,519,631</u>: Semantic Diff and Automerge, based on work I did during a 2011 internship at Microsoft

# Technology Experience

**Most recently:** C/C++, Windows Driver Model, InfiniBand RDMA. These are all still top of mind.

**In the past:** OpenGL, Qt, Python, Java, Linux shells, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL. I have used these for nontrivial projects in the past, but it's been a while.

## Education

I graduated from Brown University in 2013 with a B.S. in Computer Science, with a 3.8 GPA. Relevant coursework:

Software System Design

Computer Networks

Introduction to Multiprocessor Synchronization

3D Game Engines

Design and Analysis of Algorithms

Introduction to Computational Linguistics

**Operating Systems** 

Operating Systems Implementation Lab

Models of Computation

Interactive Computer Graphics (Graduate-level)

Introduction to Computer Systems Security

Introduction to Android Game Development

**Introduction to Computer Graphics** 

**Introduction to Computer Systems** 

The Matrix in Computer Science (Linear Algebra)

Introduction to Software Engineering

Discrete Structures and Probability

The most recent version of this document is available at <a href="http://www.davekilian.com/resume.html">http://www.davekilian.com/resume.html</a>.